Guide to the George Howard Edward Smith Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Howard Edward Smith papers
1917-1962
MS 458
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
31
(82 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, printed material, and miscellanea documenting the personal and professional life of George H.E. Smith, an author, educator at Yale University, director of the League of Nations, Non-Partisan Association of Detroit, Michigan, and secretary, staff director, and consultant to the U.S. Senate Republican Policy Committee (1944-1962). The papers document Smith's work for the Republican Policy Committee through memoranda, correspondence, handbooks, articles, newsletters, and printed material. These same materials were distributed to Republican senators for use in speeches, position papers, and political campaigns. The Republican Party position on such issues as domestic policy, economic policy, elections, foreign relations, and political parties is detailed. The workings of the Committee itself can be charted through the minutes of meetings, correspondence, and subject files, as can the development of the Committee staff. Writings and general correspondence focus on Smith's literary work on topics including: national politics, political parties, and domestic and foreign policies. Charles A. Beard, James Couzens, John Danaher, Roman Gorski, and Lindsay Rogers are primary correspondents. Additional material documents Smith's financial work as director of the Detroit, Michigan, League of Nations office, his teaching career at Yale University, and his personal life.
Smith, George H. E. (George Howard Edward), 1898-1962
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Josephine Smith, 1965.
Existence and Location of Copies
Correspondence with Charles A. Beard also available on microfilm (350 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM19.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, printed material, and miscellanea documenting the personal and professional life of George H. E. Smith, an author, educator at Yale University, director of the League of Nations, Non-Partisan Association of Detroit, Michigan, and secretary, staff director and consultant to the U. S. Senate Republican Policy Committee (1944-1962).
The papers document Smith's work for the Republican Policy Committee through memoranda, correspondence, handbooks, articles, newsletters, and printed material. These same materials were distributed to Republican senators for use in speeches, position papers, and political campaigns. The Republican Party position on such issues as domestic policy, economic policy, elections, foreign relations,and political parties is detailed. The workings of the Committee itself can be charted through the minutes of meetings, correspondence, and subject files, as can the development of the Committee staff.
Writings and general correspondence focus on Smith's literary work on topics including: national politics, political parties, and domestic and foreign policies. Charles A. Beard, James Couzens, John Danaher, Roman Gorski, and Lindsay Rogers are primary correspondents.
Additional material documents Smith's financial work as director of the Detroit, Michigan, League of Nations office, his teaching career at Yale University, and his personal life.
The Smith Papers, totalling thirty-one (31) linear feet and eighty-two (82) boxes, are arranged in five series.
SERIES I, LEAGUE OF NATIONS, NON-PARTISAN ASSOCIATION, contains correspondence, papers, and printed material from Smith's tenure as director of the Detroit, Michigan office of this organization. The bulk of correspondence consists of letters with Edsel Ford and his secretary, A. J. Lepine. Ford was the primary source of funding for the organization. Financial records of the office (folders 14-21) and printed material (folders 24-25) are also included.
SERIES II, GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, contains Smith's letters to and from friends and associates, 1931-1962. This series is arranged in two sections:1931-1943 and 1944-1962. Cross references between these sections link correspondents whose letters appear in both sections. The majority of correspondents are represented by small amounts of routine letters. Important correspondents include: Charles A. Beard, James Couzens, John Danaher, Roman Gorski, Lindsay Rogers, and Arthur Vandenberg.
Letters exchanged between Smith and Charles A. Beard are available on microfilm (HM 19). A primary topic discussed in Smith's correspondence with Beard, other academic figures, and U. S. senators is the content of Smith's writings on U. S. politics and international politics.
SERIES III, SENATE REPUBLICAN POLICY COMMITTEE, contains Smith's office files as secretary, staff director, and consultant to the committee, 1944-1962. This series includes memoranda, correspondence, writings, and research files generated by Smith. The series is arranged in eleven sections.
Intra-office correspondence, General correspondence, and Party conference correspondence(boxes 7-12) contain letters and memoranda on the organizational and planning aspects of the committee and its staff, including material on the Republican Steering Committee, the organization which preceded the Policy Committee. Individual correspondents include Republican senators, congressional staff members, government officials and employees, political figures, scholars, and private citizens. Smith and his staff researched numerous topics for Republican senators, the Republican National Committee, the Republican Senatorial Campaign Committee, and the Republican Party Conference. Among these topics are: "Borrowed staff," which is the practice of Senate committees and sub-committee allocating personnel from federal offices (folders 201-204), the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (folders 231-234), and "Science legislation" (folders 260-268).
Individual correspondents of importance in these sections include: Charles A. Beard, Edwin Borchard, and senators Henry Styles Bridges, Prescott Sheldon Bush, John Danaher, Homer Ferguson, Barry Goldwater, William Jenner, William Knowland, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., and William Reed.
Circular memoranda, Blue cover staff handbooks, and Articles contain numerous papers prepared for Republican senators.Circular memoranda(boxes 13-14) contains confidential information sheets disseminated to all Republican senators from 1944-1960.Blue cover staff handbooks(boxes 15-19) consists of sixty-four studies prepared from 1944-1960. These handbooks are lengthy, detailed reports on political and legislative topics of the day.Articles(boxes 20-23) contains a numerical and chronological section of "articles" prepared by the Policy Committee staff for specific Republican senators. Many Republican senators received material from the Policy Committee, including Henry Styles Bridges, Homer Ferguson, Robert A. Taft, Arthur Vandenberg, and Keith Wherry.
Election campaign handbooks and Senate Minority/Majority memos contain printed material produced by the Policy Committee. Handbooks (boxes 24-25) consist of notebooks and reports which detail major issues facing Republican candidates in the election years of 1950, 1952, 1956 and 1958.Minority/Majority memos(boxes 26-27) consists of weekly newsletters circulated to Republican officials.
Subject files(boxes 28-56) contains printed material, clippings, speeches, papers, and research material accumulated by Smith. This section is arranged in two sub-sections: General and Special reference. Material in this section provided the information used in the preparation of Circular memoranda, Blue cover staff handbooks, Articles, Election campaign handbooks, and Senate Minority/Majority memos. Important topics in this section include: Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (folders 647-51), Congress (folders 674-693), Elections (folders 707-732), Foreign policy (folders 757-765), National Science Foundation (folders 809-826), New Deal (folders 831-865), Patterns of legislation (folders 898-956), Republican Party (folders 1045-1055), and Staffing and operations (folders 1070-1076).
Minutes(boxes 57-60) contains drafts and conference copies of the minutes of meetings for the Minority/Majority Conference Committee of the Policy (Steering) Committee from 1944-1948.
Printed material(boxes 61-63) contains a variety of items on national politics and elections.
SERIES IV, WRITINGS, contains drafts and reference material for Smith's writings.Books-drafts, Books-miscellaneous, Books-reference files, and Books-research notes contain material on those volumes which Smith authored or co-authored.
Articles, Speeches, and Book reviews contain drafts of those types of writings.Miscellaneous contains unidentified writings.
SERIES V, STUDENT PAPERS, TEACHING MATERIALS, AND PERSONAL PAPERS, contains Smith's student papers from the University of Michigan and Yale University, his teaching materials on courses he conducted at Yale University and elsewhere, and personal papers of family members.
Biographical / Historical
George Howard Smith was born on December 2, 1898 in Astoria, Long Island, New York. He was a political scientist, author, and secretary of the U.S. Senate Republican Policy Committee. Smith died in Shelton, Connecticut on December 3, 1962. Smith attended the University of Michigan (M.A. 1928) and Yale University Graduate School, fellow (1935-1936). He authored several works on U.S. politics with Charles A. Beard and others. Smith married Elizabeth Wehner in 1919 and had two children, Nancy Jean and Mary Elizabeth. He married Josephine Burba in 1942.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. League of Nations, Non-Partisan Association, 1927-1931. II. General Correspondence, 1931-1962. III. Senate Republican Policy Committee, 1944-1960. IV. Writings, 1926-1959. V. Student Papers, Teaching Materials and Personal Papers, 1917-1959.
Legislation -- United States; Political parties -- United States; Political scientists in government; United States -- Economic policy; United States -- Foreign relations; United States -- Politics and government; Authors; Educators; Beard, Charles A. (Charles Austin), 1874-1948; Borchard, Edwin, 1884-1951; Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961; Bush, Prescott Sheldon, 1895-1972; Butler, John Marshall, 1897-1978; Couzens, James, 1872-1936; Danaher, John Anthony, 1899-; Dirksen, Everett McKinley, 1896-1969; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Ferguson, Homer, 1888-1982; Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stevenson), 1890-1972; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998; Gorski, Roman S.; Jenner, William E. (William Ezra), 1908-1985; Knowland, William F. (William Fife), 1908-1974; Milbank, Albert B.; Reed, William R., 1908-; Rogers, Lindsay, 1891-1970; Smith, George H. E. (George Howard Edward), 1898-1962; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; United States. Congress. Senate -- Officials and employees; League of Nations; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- LEAGUE OF NATIONS, NON-PARTISAN ASSOCIATION, 1927-1931; Series I; 0.5; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, papers and printed material arranged alphabetically by the type of material.
  Correspondence and printed material files are arranged in chronological order. Papers files are arranged alphabetically by their subject and then chronologically.
  - Correspondence
    - 1927 January - 1931 October (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - Papers
    - Administrative, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
    - Financial: balance sheets, budgets, statements, ledgers, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 14-21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-1931, undated (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - Printed material, 1927-1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1931-1962; Series II; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: 1931-1943, and 1944-1962. Each section contains an alphabetical arrangement of correspondence by the name of the individual or organization.
  Cross reference citations are provided for individuals and organizations represented in each section.
  An asterisk next to the name of an individual or organization signifies that ten or more items are present for that correspondent.
  - 1931-1943
    - American Academy of Political and Social Science - American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1932-1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - American Political Science Association, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      General note
      See also: box 2, folder 29-33
    - American Political Science Review, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - American State Papers (*), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 29-33)
      See also: box 2, folder 27
    - Atkins, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Barnes and Noble, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Beard, Charles A. and Mary R. (*), 1932-1942 (Box 2, Folder 36-45)
    - Bennett, Arthur A., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bethel, Lawrence L., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Booth, Frazier C., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bryson, Lyman, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Buxton Incorporated, 1940 December - 1942 April (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1941 February - June (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Chalmers, Henry (*), 1933 March - 1934 April (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Chase National Bank, 1936 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Committee for America Self-contained, 1934 January 4, February 8 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Connecticut, State Department of Education, Bureau of Field Service (*), 1935 February - October (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Consumers' Research, Inc. (*), 1932 August - 1933 June (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Counts, George S., 1935 May 1-2 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Couzens, James (*), 1932 December - 1935 March (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Coyle, David Cushman, 1933 March - 1936 February (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Crane, Robert T., 1935 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Cummings, Hilton C., undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Current History (*), 1941 October - 1942 January (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Dahlberg, Arthur, 1932 November - December (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Danaher, John Anthony (*), 1931 October - 1944 January (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Davis, E. H., 1935 April 12 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Department of Commerce, 1938 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dirlam, Riba B., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Douglass, Lucy (Mrs.), 1935 July 5, [6] (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Elsifor, Cartage Co., 1934 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Faeth, Henry J., 1935 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1938, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Federal Reserve Board, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Field, Robert S., 1934 April 21 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Fitzmaurice, Lillian, 1934, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Furniss, Edgar S., 1941 May (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Gaffrey, Norman Henry, 1940 January - 1943 July (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Gorski, Roman S. (*), 1934 April - 1940 November (Box 2, Folder 67-68)
    - Gorski, Roman S. (*), 1941 January - 1943 October (Box 3, Folder 69-71)
    - Harper's. Magazine --, 1940 March - 1942 October (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Hartford, City of, Chief of Police, 1937 October 19, 21 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Harvard College Library--, 1932 December 3, 13, 16 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Hooper, Joseph C., 1934 May - 1941 April (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Institute of Human Fellowship
      - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 75-76)
    - Inter-American Commercial Arbitration Commission, 1940 March 12, 18 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Ivey and Ellington, Inc., 1943 February 4, 8, 12 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Kellems, Vivian, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Keppel, Bob, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Kiernan,Vincent, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Knight, Dorothy S., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Knox, Frank, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Koopman, G. Robert, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Lowenstein, Karl, 1936, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Lonergan, Augustine, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.(*), 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 83-84)
    - MacMillan Company (*), 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 85-86)
    - "Management Counselors" (*), 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Mannweiler, C. L., 1935 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Matteson, David M., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Milbank, Albert B., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Murphy, Frank, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - New York Times Book Review, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - New Republic, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Perkins, Milo, [1942] (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Perry, C. Edward, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Plumb Memorial Library, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Poole, N. H., 1934 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Reeves, Jesse S., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Research Institute of America, Inc., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Robinson, Florence (Mrs. Edward S.), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Rogers, Lindsay (*), 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Romeike Press Clipping Bureau, 1933, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Saul, Harvey, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Seidler, Frank R., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Seth Thomas Clocks, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Seward, H. L., 1931 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Simon, Herman, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1934, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Social Studies (*), 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 98-99)
    - Spykman, Nicholas, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Stevenson, A. R., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Stevenson, Beatrice E., 1933 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Stimson, Henry L., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Stockover, Julia M., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Sundius, Herbert W., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Taft, Horace D., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Takayanagi, Kenzo, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - United States, Works Progress Administration, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - University of Pennsylvania Law Review (*), 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Viking Press, Inc., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Wallace, Schuyler C., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Walser, Frank, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Walther, Ed, 1936 June (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Westerfield, Ray, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Williams, Constance, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Yale University Library, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Unidentified, 1933-1942 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - 1944-1962
    - American Political Science Association
      - General, 1944 April - 1945 February (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - Committee on Political Parties, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 112-113)
      - Committee on Political Parties, Sub-Committee on National Conventions, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - Committee on Political Parties, Sub-Committee to Follow-up on the 1950 Report (Box 4, Folder 114)
        - General, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 115-116)
        - Bibliography, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
        - Reports
          - General, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 118-120)
          - Toward a More Responsible Two-Party System: A Report ...
            - Annotated copy, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 121)
            - Versions I-IV, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 122-125)
            - Miscellaneous data and notes, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 126-132)
      - Cooperative Research Project on Convention Delegates, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 133-136)
    - Anger, George W. and Mae, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Annals ..., American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Atwater, Frank, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Beard, Charles A. (*), 1944-1948 (Box 6, Folder 139-143)
    - Bethel, Lawrence L. (*), 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Buck, C. Douglas, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - "Colombia--South America" (*), 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 146-148)
    - Crowe, Dr. Samuel J., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Crowell, (Thomas Y.) Company, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - David, Paul T., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Davis, William C., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Denker, David, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Dunlap, Fred E., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Ember, William, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Ferguson, Leroy C., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - [Fischer, Frederick?], 1944 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Foundation for Foreign Affairs, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Glover Associates, Inc., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Gorski, Roman S., 1950 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Gross, Bertram M., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Hitchcock, William Harold, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Hooper, Joseph C., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - "Incolda" (Instituto Columbiano de Administration), 1959-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 157-158)
    - "Interstate Commerce Commission", 1949-[1954?] (Box 6, Folder 159-160)
    - Isaacson, Pauline, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Litchfield, Edward H., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Long, Norton E., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Lux, Paul, 1945 September (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc. (*), 1944-1954 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - McIntosh, Dempster, 1960 January (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Martin, Edward A., 1949 May (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Measure, 1950 August (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Mughmore, Don, 1949 August (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Neergaard, Richard H., 1950 May (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - New Mexico Highlands University, 1950 July (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Pleuther, Willard A., 1951 January (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Plumb Memorial Library, 1947 September (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Possidente, William, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Reader's Digest, 1957 April (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Rodier, Anthony, 1945-1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Rotary International, 1950 November (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - Seth Thomas Clocks, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - "Shaio-Sedalona" (*), 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 171-172)
    - Shelton High School, 1959 June (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Smith, Josephine J.,(Burba) (*), 1954 August - October (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Smith, Nancy Jean, 1945 March (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Smith, William, 1945 March (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Stockover, Julia M., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Taylor, Robert G., 1948-1952 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Truman, David B., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - U. S. Adjutant-General's Office, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Warring, Dr. Frederick C., 1944, undated (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Whittington, Jack H., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Willey, G. H., III, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Unidentified, [1944] (Box 6, Folder 179)
- SENATE REPUBLICAN POLICY COMMITTEE, 1932 -1960; Series III; 21 linear feet (57 boxes)
  This series is arranged in several sections:
  Intra-office correspondence
  General correspondence
  Party conference correspondence
  Circular memoranda
  Blue cover staff handbooks
  Articles
  Election campaign handbooks
  Senate Minority/Majority memos
  Subject files
  Minutes
  Printed material
  General correspondence, Party conference correspondence, and Subject files are arranged alphabetically. The remaining sections are arranged chronologically.
  Folders with asterisks(*) contain ten or more items.
  - Intra-office correspondence
    - 1944 May - 1960 Feb, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 180-195)
  - General correspondence
    - Alken, Lola (Pierotti), 1949 May (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - American Political Science Review, 1949 May (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Andrews, John, 1947 Jan, March (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Beckley, Harold R., 1947 (Box 7, Folder 197)